{
  "nb6fUZ3QSZcDtTlsqMHCr4Vbvou2" : {
    "cards" : {
      "0" : {
        "back" : "bom senso",
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "Due to their lack of humanity and ***common sense***",
        "id" : "0",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "notes" : [ "Due to their lack of humanity and common sense." ],
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 1
      },
      "-MYQ0vXGS-FIllasHd7e" : {
        "back" : "something that a person finds especially annoying",
        "createdAt" : 1618588543292,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "Pet peeve",
        "id" : "-MYQ0vXGS-FIllasHd7e",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "notes" : [ "This is one of my biggest pet peeves, you should not do this" ],
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYQR7aG31qt4FglzNPy" : {
        "back" : "ðŸ‘‡",
        "createdAt" : 1618589754962,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "How to answer to **nice to meet you**?",
        "id" : "-MYQR7aG31qt4FglzNPy",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "notes" : [ "Thank you! Good to meet you as well", "Nice to meet you too", "Nice to meet you as well", "Pleased to meet you", "Likewise", "you too!" ],
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "tags" : [ "question" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYRDE_6ePR7c6U-uS7u" : {
        "back" : "Tristeza ",
        "createdAt" : 1618602459866,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "he understood the ***sorrow*** and discontent underlying his brother's sigh",
        "id" : "-MYRDE_6ePR7c6U-uS7u",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYRDE_7WfJLQidLZHpQ" : {
        "back" : "salvar o amor ***atravÃ©s da*** tristeza",
        "createdAt" : 1618602459866,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "save your love ***through*** sorrow",
        "id" : "-MYRDE_7WfJLQidLZHpQ",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQD" : {
        "back" : "Este escudo Ã© um monumento para uma era remota",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629650,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "This shield is a monument to a ***bygone*** era",
        "id" : "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQD",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQE" : {
        "back" : "Ei, vocÃª recuperou sua ***manga*** (da camisa) de volta",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629650,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "Hey, you got your ***sleeve*** back",
        "id" : "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQE",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQF" : {
        "back" : "folha de pagamento",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629650,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "The company is growing fast, adding another 100 employees to its ***payroll*** over the last year.",
        "id" : "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQF",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQG" : {
        "back" : "To prevent people from getting into (an area) by putting a line of people or objects around or in front of it. In pt \"Isolar\"",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "Theyâ€™ve ***cordoned off*** the whole area because of a suspected bomb.",
        "id" : "-MYlX05jOZqFh32UGrQG",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "notes" : [ "Theyâ€™ve cordoned off the whole area because of a suspected bomb." ],
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa5" : {
        "back" : "Remain firmly in one's place",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "You'd better ***sit tight*** and I'll call the doctor.",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa5",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa6" : {
        "back" : "*ganhando* assim, desse modo, portanto",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "students perform in hospitals, ***thereby*** gaining a deeper awareness of the therapeutic power of music",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa6",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa7" : {
        "back" : "O GRC os acusou de *** abrigar *** fugitivos internacionais.  \nHarbor = Porto,  \nto harbor = Abrigar",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "The GRC accused them of ***harboring*** international fugitives",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa7",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "notes" : [ "to harbor a criminal" ],
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "tags" : [ "verb" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 1
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa8" : {
        "back" : "abet: to help or encourage someone to do something wrong or illegal (ser cÃºmplice de)\n\n---\nO GRC os acusou de ***acobertar fugitivos*** internacionais",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "The GRC accused them of ***abetting*** international fugitives",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa8",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa9" : {
        "back" : "grudge: A bad or angry feeling towards someone because of something they did in the past (rancor)",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "i had no **grudges** for what you thought you had to do",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxa9",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "notes" : [ "i had no grudges for what you thought you had to do" ],
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "tags" : [ "plural" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 1
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaA" : {
        "back" : "NÃ£o faÃ§a essa de homem ***amargo*** comigo",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "Don't do that ***bitter*** old man thing with me",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaA",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaB" : {
        "back" : "gramado",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "Cleaning the **lawn** is highly recommended before each winter.",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaB",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "tags" : [ "noun" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaC" : {
        "back" : "jurar fidelidade",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "Let us **pledge allegiance** here and say aloud our promise to our new country.",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaC",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 1
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaD" : {
        "back" : "eu pedi um favor",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "i called in a favor",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaD",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-08",
        "repetitions" : 3,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaF" : {
        "back" : "rude, mÃ¡ *pessoa*, not kind",
        "createdAt" : 1618960629651,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "she is a very **mean** person",
        "id" : "-MYlX05kKq4SFihqOxaF",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "notes" : [ "she is a very mean person" ],
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MYm1eEJVJbefnbbvKKP" : {
        "back" : "We use the present perfect: for something that started in the past and continues in the present: She has lived in Liverpool all her life.\nWe normally use the present perfect continuous to emphasise that something is still continuing in the present: She has been living in Liverpool all her life.",
        "createdAt" : 1618970587334,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "what is **present perfect** and present perfect continuous? And how to use it?",
        "id" : "-MYm1eEJVJbefnbbvKKP",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "tags" : [ "question" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MZVK0CJiXQj9B9D0Oct" : {
        "back" : "Was: singular -> I was, You were, He was, She was, It was  \nWere -> We were, You were, They were",
        "createdAt" : 1619745077658,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "When to use was vs were?",
        "id" : "-MZVK0CJiXQj9B9D0Oct",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "tags" : [ "question" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-MaaIOC54rJfJo5flWmP" : {
        "back" : "no meio de algo, em pleno\n\n> experiencing or doing something that is difficult, unpleasant, or painful",
        "createdAt" : 1621994658955,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "India is ***in the throes of a*** horrendous COVID surge",
        "id" : "-MaaIOC54rJfJo5flWmP",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "wrongReviews" : 1
      },
      "-MaaIOC54rJfJo5flWmQ" : {
        "back" : "something or someone that causes you a lot of trouble, often when that thing or person should be helping you.\n> um estorvo",
        "createdAt" : 1621994658955,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "After a certain age, a car's just a ***liability***",
        "id" : "-MaaIOC54rJfJo5flWmQ",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-06-14",
        "repetitions" : 2,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-McCThBir1Xwg_53Lwen" : {
        "back" : "to develop in a particular way or in a successful way\n> NÃ³s vamos ver como as coisas se desenvolvem",
        "createdAt" : 1625377120398,
        "diff" : 0.05,
        "front" : "We'll have to see how things ***pan out***",
        "id" : "-McCThBir1Xwg_53Lwen",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-07-03",
        "repetitions" : 1,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-McCThBir1Xwg_53Lweo" : {
        "back" : "a large, thick piece, especially of food",
        "createdAt" : 1625377120398,
        "diff" : 0.05,
        "front" : "a ***hunk*** of bread",
        "id" : "-McCThBir1Xwg_53Lweo",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-07-03",
        "repetitions" : 1,
        "tags" : [ "noun" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-McCThBir1Xwg_53Lwep" : {
        "back" : "vai ***levar*** a outra",
        "createdAt" : 1625377120398,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "One thing will **lead** to the other",
        "id" : "-McCThBir1Xwg_53Lwep",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-07-03",
        "repetitions" : 1,
        "tags" : [ "verb" ],
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      },
      "-Mdk0FMyg2V--sxl8uSx" : {
        "back" : "test",
        "createdAt" : 1625378956541,
        "diff" : 0,
        "front" : "test",
        "id" : "-Mdk0FMyg2V--sxl8uSx",
        "lang" : "en",
        "lastReview" : "2021-07-03",
        "repetitions" : 1,
        "wrongReviews" : 0
      }
    }
  }
}
